Jerry Ryle

jerry@ryle.io +1 (650) 400-9551 jerryryle.com

I am an engineering leader with a strong software engineering background and a breadth of experience in product development. I build and lead teams that execute well. I work cross-functionally and with all levels of leadership to meet our business objectives while shipping products that our customers love.

EXPERIENCE

Verily Life Sciences, South San Francisco, CA Head of Medical Devices Software, 2019-2022

- Led the team of embedded, mobile, and cloud developers that created the software that runs Verily's highly-integrated medical devices and connects them to the cloud
- Brought three significant hardware and software products from early development to shipping:
 - Verily Retinal Camera camera that uses AI for low-cost, high-quality detection of diabetic retinopathy
 - Verily Patch cloud-enabled adhesive patch that regularly measures an individual's body temperature
 - Verily Study Watch sensor-packed, wearable device for non-invasive, continuous monitoring
- Kept my team lean and productive amidst shifting company priorities; helped plan and execute initiatives to better align Verily's hardware investment with company strategy

Alpine Health, Mountain View, CA

V.P. Engineering, 2017-2018

- Hired and led a cross-functional team of engineers and consultants to build a revolutionary consumer health device
- Produced our pivotal patent application, which helped secure us a funding round of \$30M
- Bootstrapped the company: set up payroll and benefits, hired development partners, created interview process, defined peer review and feedback process, codified development methodology, and set engineering goals

Mindtribe Product Engineering, San Francisco, CA Partner and V.P. Engineering, 2001-2017

- Built Mindtribe into a 40-person, world-class engineering consultancy that was acquired by Accenture
- Redesigned our engineering methodology to improve outcomes, which differentiated Mindtribe's services and led
 to larger and more interesting contracts
- Brought Agile values to hardware engineering, enabling rapid product development
- Responsible for business development, sales, program management, process development, strategy, hiring, engineering leadership, and technical execution
- · Helped numerous startups scale their technologies and their teams from MVP to mass-market
- Select projects:

Stealth Company, Encrypted Communications Device, 2015-2016

- Led a cross-functional team to take a complex, consumer electronics device for encrypted voice communications from concept through manufacturing in less than a year
- Solved technical challenges relating to security, testability, and manufacturability

Adobe, Project Parallel, 2012

- Led a team of developers and designers to create Line, Adobe's Ink and Slide showcase app
- Taught the rapid development methodology that we used on Line to Adobe's other app teams

Square, Stand, 2012

- · Led a cross-functional team to deliver Stand, Square's point-of sale solution for brick-and-mortar retailers
- Structured and ran this program from concept through manufacturing
- · Set clear priorities for the team, which allowed us go from concept to shipping product in less than a year

EDUCATION

California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo, CA | B.S., Computer Engineering, Class of 2000

PATENTS